Guide to the Robert Moses Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Inventory, 1934-(1952-1970)
  - 1957: 3rd volume
    - SPEECHES, RELEASES, ETC.
      - SUNKEN MEADOW STATE PARKWAY AND EXPANDED SUNKEN MEADOW STATE PARK ON NORTH SHORE OF LONG ISLAND, SMITHTOWN, L. I. (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - SWIMMING POOL IN CENTRAL PARK OVER WNYC (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - THROGS NECK BRIDGE AND APPROACHES, COMMENCEMENT OF WORK (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - TOPSOIL FOR NEW YORK PARKS BY ROBERT MOSES--WNYC (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - 30th ANNIVERSARY OF HOWARD S. CULLMAN AS COMMISSIONER OF PORT OF NEW YORK AUTHORITY--STATEMENT OF ROBERT MOSES (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - WEST SIDE ASSOCIATION OF COMMERCE LUNCHEON--TALK BY ROBERT MOSES (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - YOUTH PROBLEM--ROBERT MOSES' LETTER TO MAYOR WAGNER (Box 2B, Folder 1)
  - 1960: 1st volume
    - BOOKS--MISCELLANEOUS:
      - NOW OR NEVER, A BOLD NEW PROGRAM FOR OUTDOOR RECREATION, CONSERVATION DEPARTMENT (Box 2B, Folder 2)
      - NOW OR NEVER, A BOLD NEW PROGRAM FOR OUTDOOR RECREATION, DEPARTMENT OF CONSERVATION--STATE COUNCIL OF PARKS (Box 2B, Folder 2)
      - INFORMATION BULLETIN … $75 MILLION PARK AND RECREATION LAND ACQUISITION BOND ACT (Box 2B, Folder 2)
      - VOTE YES ON PROPOSITION #1 ($75 MILLION PARK AND RECREATION LAND ACQUISITION BOND ACT) (Box 2B, Folder 2)
      - A PROGRAM FOR STATE PARK LAND ACQUISITION, DECEMBER 19 (Box 2B, Folder 2)
      - 11 NEW PARK AREAS--FOR THE CITY OF NEW YORK, DECEMBER 19 (Box 2B, Folder 2)
      - LONG ISLAND STATE PARK EXPANSION, DECEMBER 19 (Box 2B, Folder 2)
      - ARTERIAL PROGRESS, QUARTERLY REPORTS ON METROPOLITAN ARTERIAL SYSTEM, FEBRUARY AND JUNE (Box 2B, Folder 2)
      - TITLE 1 PROGRESS QUARTERLY REPORT, SLUM CLEARANCE PROJECTS, JANUARY 29 (Box 2B, Folder 2)
      - 26 YEARS OF PROGRESS, CITY OF NEW YORK, DEPT. OF PARKS, JANUARY 1, 1960 (Box 2B, Folder 2)
      - TRIBOROUGH BRIDGE AND TUNNEL AUTHORITY ANNUAL REPORT 1959, DATED FEBRUARY 19, 1960 (Box 2B, Folder 2)
      - BROOKLYN--QUEENS EXPRESSWAY, JANUARY 5 (Box 2B, Folder 2)
      - HARTFORD PAVILION IN CENTRAL PARK, MAY 2 (Box 2B, Folder 2)
      - PALISADES HISTORY 1900-1960 (Box 2B, Folder 2)
      - PALISADES ANNUAL REPORT--1960 (Box 2B, Folder 2)
    - MAGAZINE AND NEWSPAPER ARTICLES:
      - LONG ISLAND DAILY PRESS: FUTURE PARK NEEDS. MOSES Rx FOR PARKS: LOTS MORE LAND AND MONEY. JANUARY 18 (Box 2B, Folder 2)
      - LONG ISLAND COMMERCIAL REVIEW: IMPORTANT ARTERIAL IMPROVEMENTS SCHEDULED FOR L. I. AREA IN 1960. JANUARY 18 (Box 2B, Folder 2)
      - HERALD TRIBUNE: MOSES ON PARK RESERVOIRS. MARCH 4 (Box 2B, Folder 2)
      - TOWN & COUNTRY: ROBERT MOSES TALKS ABOUT NEW YORK. MARCH (Box 2B, Folder 2)
      - STATEN ISLAND ADVANCE: MOSES TO ISLAND: FUTURE UP TO YOU. APRIL 30 (Box 2B, Folder 2)
      - LONG ISLAND SUNDAY PRESS: MOSES URGES EXPANSION OF CITY'S BEACHFRONT. MAY 15 (Box 2B, Folder 2)
      - JOURNAL AMERICAN: MOSES PREVIEWS FAIR: GREATEST EVER. JUNE 12 (Box 2B, Folder 2)
      - ESQUIRE: "in 'de. fin' a. ble NEW YORK. PUNGENT COMMENTS ON THE DIFFICULTY OF DESCRIBING NEW YORK, BY ITS INDISPENSABLE MAN, ROBERT MOSES". JULY (Box 2B, Folder 2)
      - STATEMENT TO THE PRESS BY ROBERT MOSES, JULY 13 (COMMENTS REGARDING NEWBOLD MORRIS' STATEMENT ATTACKING RESTRICTIONS IN MUNICIPAL PARKS IN WESTCHESTER AND OTHER SUBURBAN COUNTIES) (Box 2B, Folder 2)
  - 1960: 2nd volume
    - SPEECHES AND RELEASES:
      - ALBANY, N. Y., JUNE 6 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        General
        REMARKS BY R.M. ON MUNICIPAL AND STATE GOVERNMENT, AT A LUNCHEON OF THE OFFICE FOR LOCAL GOVERNMENT, STATE TEACHERS COLLEGE.
      - ASTOR HOTEL, N. Y. C., AUGUST 17 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE ANNUAL CONGRESS OF THE AMERICAN PUBLIC WORKS ASSOCIATION.
      - BABYLON, N. Y., JULY 31 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE DEDICATION OF PHELPS LANE TOWN PARK.
      - BEAR MOUNTAIN, N. Y., MAY 13 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT 60th ANNIVERSARY OF PALISADES INTERSTATE PARK.
      - BROOKLYN, N. Y., JANUARY 5 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE OPENING OF THE BROOKLYN-QUEENS EXPRESS WAY, NAVY YARD SECTION.
      - CONCORD, N. H., MAY 20 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. TO THE FACULTY AT ST. PAUL'S SCHOOL, "PUBLIC SERVICE AS A CAREER".
      - CONCORD, N. H., MAY 21 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. TO SENIORS AND JUNIORS AT ST. PAUL'S SCHOOL, "WHAT MAKES DEMOCRACY WORK".
      - DOWNTOWN, ATHLETIC CLUB, N. Y. C., FEBRUARY 19 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS BY R.M. AT THE 50th ANNUAL LUNCHEON OF THE NEW YORK STATE WATERWAYS ASSOCIATION, IN HONOR OF SENATOR ROBERT KERR.
      - FREEPORT, N. Y., OCTOBER 8 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS BY R.M., FREEPORT GRADE SEPARATION.
      - GARDEN CITY, N. Y., MARCH 15 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT DINNER TO MILTON GOUL AT GARDEN CITY HOTEL.
      - HARTFORD PAVILION, N. Y. C., MARCH 14 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        RELEASE R.M.'s ANNOUNCEMENT OF MR. HUNTINGTON HARTFORD'S GIFT TO THE PARKS DEPARTMENT.
      - HAYDEN PLANETARIUM, N. Y. C., JANUARY 29 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE RE-OPENING OF THE HAYDEN PLANETARIUM, AMERICAN MUSEUM OF NATURAL HISTORY.
      - HOTEL COMMODORE N.Y.C., MAY 3 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. ON WORLD'S FAIR 1964-1965, AT A DINNER OF THE GREATER NEW YORK PLANNING COUNCIL.
      - HOTEL PICCADILLY N. Y. C., APRIL 21 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        TALK BY R.M. ON RECEIVING A MERITORIOUS CITATION AND PLAQUE FROM THE AFFILIATED YOUNG DEMOCRATS.
      - JONES BEACH, N. Y., JANUARY 20 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        STATEMENT OF R.M. REGARDING "FLYING BILLBOARDS" "A GLIMPSE INTO THE NEAR FUTURE IF WE DON'T WATCH OUT".
      - JONES BEACH, N. Y., SEPTEMBER 17 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT DEDICATION OF BRONZE MEMORIAL TO TOWNSEND SCUDDER, AT MARINE THEATRE.
      - LINCOLN SQUARE, N. Y. C., MAY 3 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT DEDICATION OF FORDHAM AT LINCOLN SQUARE CORNERSTONE CEREMONIES, FORDHAM UNIVERSITY SCHOOL OF LAW.
      - LONG ISLAND EXPRESSWAY, N. Y., OCTOBER 8 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT OPENING OF SECTION FROM GUINEA WOODS ROAD TO JERICHO TURNPIKE.
      - LOTUS CLUB, N. Y. C., FEBRUARY 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. NINETIETH ANNIVERSARY OF THE FOUNDING OF THE LOTUS CLUB, "THE IDEA OF A CLUB".
      - MASSENA, N. Y., MAY 18 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M., AT DINNER OF MASSENA CHAMBER OF COMMERCE, HOLIDAY INN.
      - MASSENA ON THE, ST. LAWRENCE RIVER, N. Y., MAY 19 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT AMERICAN SOCIETY OF CIVIL ENGINEERS AWARD CEREMONY.
      - NEW YORK CITY, JUNE 20 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REPLY BY R.M. TO THE AUTHOR OF MEMOIRS OF HECATE COUNTY AND TO HIS REVIEWERS, "TUSCARORA FICTION & FACT".
      - NEW YORK CITY, DECEMBER 3 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        STATEMENT BY R.M. ON THE OCCASION OF THE TWENTY-FIFTH ANNIVERSARY OF PUBLIC HOUSING IN NEW YORK CITY.
      - NIAGARA FALLS, N. Y., MAY 10 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE NIAGARA FALLS CHAMBER OF COMMERCE DINNER.
      - NIAGARA FALLS, N. Y., JUNE 20 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT A LUNCHEON OF THE NEW YORK STATE SOCIETY OF NEWSPAPER EDITORS AT TREADWAY INN, "SOME LESSONS IN CONSERVATION".
      - NIAGARA FALLS, N. Y., JUNE 21 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. ON THE OCCASION OF THE 75th ANNIVERSARY OF THE STATE RESERVATION AT NIAGARA, GOAT ISLAND, AMERICAN FALLS.
      - ROOSEVELT RACEWAY, N. Y., OCTOBER 15 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. ON THE FUTURE GROWTH OF LONG ISLAND.
      - SHERATON EAST, HOTEL, N. Y. C., OCTOBER 26 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT A LUNCHEON OF PUBLIC RELATIONS SOCIETY OF AMERICA AND THE AMERICAN PUBLIC RELATIONS ASSOCIATION.
      - STATLER HOTEL, WASHINGTON, D. C., APRIL 22 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT A MEETING OF THE AMERICAN SOCIETY OF NEWS PAPER EDITORS, "THE PRESS AND THE PUBLIC OFFICIAL".
      - TEMPLE EMANU-EL, N. Y. C., FEBRUARY 8 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE SERVICES FOR CONSTANCE LEWISOHN.
      - THE PLAYERS, N. Y. C., MARCH 22 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        INTRODUCTORY REMARKS OF R.M., PIPE MASTER AT THE PLAYERS, "NEW YORK IN 2000".
      - TOBAY TOWN BEACH, N. Y., JULY 9 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE DEDICATION OF THE BAY FRONT DEVELOPMENT.
      - WALDORF-ASTORIA, N. Y. C., APRIL 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT DINNER OF THE BOARD OF TRUSTEES OF GRAND CENTRAL HOSPITAL, ON RECEIVING THE MANHATTAN MEDAL FOR COMMUNITY SERVICE.
      - WALDORF-ASTORIA, N. Y. C., OCTOBER 25 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT A LUNCHEON OF THE NEW YORK CONVENTION AND VISITORS BUREAU, ON THE WORLD'S FAIR OF 1964-1965.
      - WESTCHESTER COUNTRY CLUB, N. Y., MAY 25 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE 10th ANNUAL DINNER OF THE WESTCHESTER COUNTY ASSOCIATION, HARRISON, N. Y.
      - YALE UNIVERSITY, CONN., MARCH 9 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        LOVETT LECTURE BY R.M., "A STATEMENT OF CHASSIS, ONE CRISIS AFTER ANOTHER" AT PIERSON COLLEGE, NEW HAVEN, CONNECTICUT.
  - 1960: 3rd volume
    - POWER AUTHORITY OF STATE OF NEW YORK:
      - ST. LAWRENCE PARK, ST. LAWRENCE POWER (FOLDER) (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - NIAGARA POWER (FOLDER) (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - NIAGARA-ST. LAWRENCE POWER PROJECTS, CONSTRUCTION PROGRESS REPORTS, JANUARY TO MAY, INCLUSIVE (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - NIAGARA POWER PROJECT, CONSTRUCTION PROGRESS REPORTS, JUNE TO DECEMBER, INCLUSIVE (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - GREAT LAKES WATER--JUNE 20 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - NIAGARA PARKS, POWER AND RELATED IMPROVEMENTS--75th ANNIVERSARY--JUNE 21 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - NIAGARA-ST. LAWRENCE TIE LINE IN ONEIDA COUNTY--AUGUST 12 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - POWER AUTHORITY, 5 YEARS OF PROGRESS--FEBRUARY 8 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - PROGRESS REPORT ON NIAGARA FRONTIER PROGRAM--OCTOBER 20 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1960: 4th volume
    - BOOKS-WORLD'S FAIR 1964-1965:
      - PREPARATION OF THE SITE, APRIL 18 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - PREPARATION OF THE SITE--SUPPLEMENTARY, APRIL 18 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - PREPARATION OF THE SITE--SECOND SUPPLEMENTARY, JULY 25 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - PRELIMINARY INFORMATION ON INTERNATIONAL EXHIBIT AREAS, AUGUST 4 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - PRELIMINARY INFORMATION ON INDUSTRIAL & TRANSPORTATION EXHIBIT AREAS, AUGUST 4 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - MAN'S ACHIEVEMENT IN AN EXPANDING UNIVERSE, AUGUST 15 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - PRELIMINARY INFORMATION ON INTERNATIONAL EXHIBIT AREAS, SEPTEMBER 6 (SPANISH) (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - INFORMATION ON INDUSTRIAL AND TRANSPORTATION EXHIBIT AREAS, NOVEMBER 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - INFORMATION ON INTERNATIONAL EXHIBIT AREAS, NOVEMBER 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - INTERIM REPORT SUGGESTING PLAN FOR PERMANENT CENTER OF SCIENCE AND EDUCATION, DECEMBER 5 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1961: 1st volume
    - POWER AUTHORITY OF STATE OF NEW YORK:
      - ATOMIC POWER, MARCH 16 (Box 3A, Folder 1)
      - NIAGARA PARKWAY-LEWISTON STATE PARK DEVELOPMENT, NOVEMBER 11 (Box 3A, Folder 1)
      - NIAGARA POWER PROJECT CONSTRUCTION PROGRESS REPORTS, JANUARY TO SEPTEMBER, INCLUSIVE (Box 3A, Folder 1)
      - NIAGARA POWER PROJECT DATA STATISTICS (Box 3A, Folder 1)
      - NIAGARA--ST. LAWRENCE ANNUAL REPORT, FEBRUARY 27 (Box 3A, Folder 1)
      - POLLUTION OF THE ILLINOIS WATERWAY, JULY 3 (Box 3A, Folder 1)
      - POWER MARKETING, JUNE 20 (Box 3A, Folder 1)
      - 1st POWER AT NIAGARA--1107 DAYS, FEBRUARY 10 (Box 3A, Folder 1)
      - ST. LAWRENCE POWER BOOKLET (Box 3A, Folder 1)
  - 1961: 2nd volume
    - BOOKS: 1961
      - A LONG ISLAND PROBLEM CONSERVING UNDERGROUND WATER, NOVEMBER 26 (Box 3A, Folder 2)
      - ARTERIAL PROGRESS, JANUARY 16 (Box 3A, Folder 2)
      - ARTERIAL PROGRESS, JULY 19 (Box 3A, Folder 2)
      - ARTERIAL PROGRESS, NOVEMBER 28 (Box 3A, Folder 2)
      - CONFLICT OF INTEREST, JULY 23 (Box 3A, Folder 2)
      - CONVERSATION--WISDOM FOR OUR TIME (Box 3A, Folder 2)
      - LINCOLN SQUARE PROGRESS-LINCOLN TOWERS CORNERSTONE CEREMONY, JULY 27 (Box 3A, Folder 2)
      - PLAN OF CAUMSETT STATE PARK AND PRELIMINARY STUDY OF APPROACH PARKWAY, MAY 22 (Box 3A, Folder 2)
      - THE ABANDONMENT OF MITCHEL FIELD, AUGUST 21 (Box 3A, Folder 2)
      - THROGS NECK BRIDGE, JANUARY 11 (Box 3A, Folder 2)
      - TRIBOROUGH BRIDGE AND TUNNEL AUTHORITY BOOKLET (Box 3A, Folder 2)
      - TRIBOROUGH BRIDGE AND TUNNEL AUTHORITY ANNUAL REPORT, FEBRUARY 24 (Box 3A, Folder 2)
    - MAGAZINE AND NEWSPAPER ARTICLES: 1961
      - COUNTY GOVERNMENT: THE STATE PARK PROGRAM, JULY (Box 3A, Folder 2)
      - NEWSDAY: ROBERT MOSES EXPOUNDS ON WORLD'S FAIR ART--(MOSES AND HIS CRITICS), JUNE 1 (Box 3A, Folder 2)
      - NEW YORK MIRROR MAGAZINE: MORE POWER TO YOU, AUGUST 13 (Box 3A, Folder 2)
      - NEW YORK TIMES: ROBERT MOSES REPLIES TO N. Y. TIMES ON CONSERVATION--"FOREST PRESERVE IN DANGER", FEBRUARY 23 (Box 3A, Folder 2)
      - NEW YORK TIMES: THE NEW NIAGARA FRONTIER, SEPTEMBER 24 (Box 3A, Folder 2)
      - NEW YORK TIMES MAGAZINE: SALUTE TO AN EAST SIDE BOY NAMED SMITH, OCTOBER 8 (Box 3A, Folder 2)
      - PITTSBURG POST--GAZETTE: THE AMERICAN CITY OF THE FUTURE, JULY 30 (Box 3A, Folder 2)
      - ROCKAWAY REVIEW: ARTERIAL SYSTEM AIDS LOCAL GROWTH, JUNE-JULY (Box 3A, Folder 2)
      - SHORE AND BEACH JOURNAL: ROBERT MOSES, NEW YORK'S MAN OF THE CENTURY--CONGRESSIONAL RECORD, OCTOBER (Box 3A, Folder 2)
  - 1961: 3rd volume
    - BOOKS--WORLD'S FAIR 1964-1965:
      - BUILDERS OF NEW YORK AND THE NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR 1964-1965, MARCH 16 (Box 3A, Folder 3)
      - FACTS ON INDUSTRIAL, STATE AND SPECIAL EXHIBITS, AUGUST (Box 3A, Folder 3)
      - FACTS ON INDUSTRIAL, STATE AND SPECIAL EXHIBITS, DECEMBER (Box 3A, Folder 3)
      - FACTS ON STATE EXHIBITS, DECEMBER (Box 3A, Folder 3)
      - FLUSHING MEADOW PARK MUNICIPAL STADIUM, OCTOBER 28 (Box 3A, Folder 3)
      - IMPROVEMENT OF FLUSHING BAY, NOVEMBER 15 (Box 3A, Folder 3)
      - INFORMATION ON INTERNATIONAL EXHIBIT AREAS (ENGLISH VERSION), JANUARY 1 (Box 3A, Folder 3)
      - INFORMATION ON INTERNATIONAL EXHIBIT AREAS (FRENCH VERSION), JANUARY 1 (Box 3A, Folder 3)
      - NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR 1964-1965--No. 1, JANUARY 16 (Box 3A, Folder 3)
      - NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR 1964-1965--No. 2, MAY 8 (Box 3A, Folder 3)
      - NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR 1964-1965--No. 3, SEPTEMBER 14 (Box 3A, Folder 3)
      - NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR 1964-1965--SUMMARY OF PLANS (Box 3A, Folder 3)
      - THE ECONOMIC BENEFITS OF THE NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR 1964-1965 (Box 3A, Folder 3)
      - THE OLYMPICS OF 1964 AND THE NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR 1964-1965 (Box 3A, Folder 3)
  - 1961: 4th volume
    - SPEECHES AND RELEASES: 1961
      - BOTANIC GARDEN, BROOKLYN, N. Y., MARCH 28 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. UPON RECEIVING THE FORSYTHIA AWARD FROM THE BROOKLYN BOTANIC GARDEN ON FORSYTHIA DAY AT THE GARDEN, MARCH 28.
      - CENTRAL PARK, N. Y., SEPTEMBER 28 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE DEDICATION OF THE CHILDREN'S ZOO IN CENTRAL PARK, SEPTEMBER 28.
      - CONCOURSE PLAZA, HOTEL, N. Y., APRIL 20 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. UPON RECEIVING A PUBLIC AFFAIRS AWARD FROM THE BRONX BOARD OF TRADE AT THE ANNUAL DINNER CONCOURSE PLAZA HOTEL, N. Y., APRIL 20.
      - FLUSHING MEADOW, N. Y., OCTOBER 28 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE GROUNDBREAKING OF THE FLUSHING MEADOW PARK MUNICIPAL STADIUM, OCTOBER 28.
      - GARDEN CITY, N. Y., SEPTEMBER 28 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE DISTINGUISHED SERVICE AWARD DINNER TO JUSTICE MARCUS CHRIST, GARDEN CITY HOTEL, SEPTEMBER 28.
      - GRAMERCY PARK, N. Y., JANUARY 29 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT A PIPE NIGHT OF THE PLAYERS HONORING SEAN O'CASEY, GRAMERCY PARK, N. Y. C., JANUARY 29.
      - HARVARD UNIVERSITY, MARCH 20 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. ON PROBLEMS OF LOCAL GOVERNMENT AT ELIOT COLLEGE, HARVARD UNIVERSITY ON THE OCCASION OF THE ANNIVERSARY OF THE BIRTH OF PRESIDENT ELIOT, MARCH 20.
      - HOTEL ASTOR, N. Y., JANUARY 13 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        "POLICING THE WATERWAYS" REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE ANNUAL DINNER OF THE NATIONAL ASSOCIATION OF ENGINE AND BOAT MANUFACTURERS, ASTOR HOTEL, JANUARY 13.
      - HOTEL ASTOR, N. Y., MAY 4 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT A LUNCHEON OF THE NEW YORK BUILDING CONGRESS AT THE HOTEL ASTOR, MAY 4.
      - HOTEL ASTOR, N. Y., NOVEMBER 15 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE ANNUAL DINNER OF THE WEST SIDE ASSOCIATION OF COMMERCE, HOTEL ASTOR, NOVEMBER 15.
      - LAKE PLACID, N. Y., SEPTEMBER 21 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        "THE FOREST PRESERVE" STATEMENT BY R.M. ADDRESSED TO THE ANNUAL MEETING OF THE ADIRONDACK PARK ASSOCIATION, LAKE PLACID, N. Y., SEPTEMBER 21.
      - LAWYERS CLUB, N. Y., JANUARY 24 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE ANNUAL LUNCHEON OF THE BEEKMAN DOWNTOWN HOSPITAL, N. Y. C., AT THE LAWYERS CLUB, JANUARY 24.
      - LINCOLN TOWERS, N. Y., JUNE 27 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT LINCOLN TOWERS' CEREMONY, JUNE 27.
      - LLOYDS NECK, N. Y., FEBRUARY 3 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. ON THE OCCASION OF THE DELIVERY OF THE DEED TO CAUMSETT STATE PARK, FEBRUARY 3.
      - LOTOS CLUB, N. Y., DECEMBER 5 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE STATE DINNER TO MARY WOODARD LASKER AT THE LOTOS CLUB, DECEMBER 5.
      - NIAGARA FALLS, N. Y., FEBRUARY 10 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE DEDICATION OF THE OBSERVATION TOWER AT NIAGARA FALLS, N. Y., FEBRUARY 10.
      - NIAGARA FALLS, N. Y., NOVEMBER 11 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        STATEMENT BY R.M. AS TO DIVERSION OF WATER AT NIAGARA FALLS MADE AT THE POWER INTAKE GATES ON THE NIAGARA PARKWAY, NOVEMBER 11.
      - NIAGARA FALLS, N. Y., JANUARY 16 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        STATEMENT BY R.M. ON NIAGARA TAXES, JANUARY 16.
      - NIAGARA UNIVERSITY, FEBRUARY 10 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        INTRODUCTORY REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE CEREMONIES INCIDENT TO THE DELIVERY OF FIRST NIAGARA POWER, IN THE GYMNASIUM OF NIAGARA UNIVERSITY, FEBRUARY 10.
      - NIAGARA UNIVERSITY, JUNE 11 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT NIAGARA UNIVERSITY COMMENCEMENT NIAGARA UNIVERSITY, N. Y., JUNE 11.
      - OHIO UNIVERSITY, NOVEMBER 9 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS BY R.M. ON MUNICIPAL AND OTHER GOVERNMENT, AT OHIO UNIVERSITY ATHENS, OHIO, NOVEMBER 9.
      - PERKINS MEMORIAL, TOWER, N. Y., OCTOBER 21 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. UNVEILING OF PLAQUE TO GEORGE W. PERKINS AT PERKINS MEMORIAL TOWER, OCTOBER 21.
      - PROSPECT PARK, N. Y., DECEMBER 22 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE OPENING OF THE PROSPECT PARK WOLLMAN RINK, DECEMBER 22.
      - ROCHDALE VILLAGE, JAMAICA, N. Y., APRIL 29 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE GROUNDBREAKING FOR ROCHDALE VILLAGE JAMAICA, QUEENS, APRIL 29.
      - ROOSEVELT HOTEL, N. Y., JUNE 20 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT A LUNCHEON OF THE SALES EXECUTIVES CLUB OF N. Y., AT THE GRAND BALLROOM, ROOSEVELT HOTEL, NEW YORK CITY, JUNE 20.
      - SALAMANCA, N. Y., JUNE 29 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT CEREMONY CELEBRATING DELIVERY OF NIAGARA POWER, SALAMANCA, N. Y., JUNE 29.
      - SEASIDE, N. Y., OCTOBER 31 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        STATEMENT OF R.M. AT THE GROUNDBREAKING CEREMONIES SEASIDE AND HAMMELS HOUSING PROJECT BEACH 108th STREET AND SHORE FRONT PARK WAY, SEASIDE, OCTOBER 31.
      - TAFT HOUSES, N. Y., OCTOBER 20 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE DEDICATION OF THE ROBERT A. TAFT PLAQUE AT TAFT HOUSES, N. Y. C., OCTOBER 20.
      - WALDORF-ASTORIA, N. Y., FEBRUARY 2 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE FORDHAM COLLEGE ALUMNI DINNER, HOTEL WALDORF-ASTORIA, N. Y. C., FEBRUARY 2.
      - WALDORF-ASTORIA, N. Y., JUNE 21 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE N. Y. LAW SCHOOL COMMENCEMENT UPON RECEIVING AN HONORARY DEGREE OF DOCTOR OF LAWS "A DECALOGUE FOR NEW LAWYERS", AT THE WALDORF-ASTORIA, N. Y. C., JUNE 21.
      - WALDORF-ASTORIA, N. Y., OCTOBER 31 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        LETTER SENT BY R.M. TO MR. COLEMAN BURKE, READ AT DINNER GIVEN IN TRIBUTE TO DR. RALPH SOCKMAN, AT WALDORF-ASTORIA, OCTOBER 31.
      - WALTHAM, MASS., MARCH 23 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. TO STUDENTS AT BRANDEIS UNIVERSITY, WALTHAM, MASSACHUSETTS, "IMPLICATIONS OF THE NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR", MARCH 23.
      - WASHINGTON, D. C., MAY 22 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
        REMARKS OF R.M. ON THE WORLD'S FAIR AT THE NATIONAL PRESS CLUB WASHINGTON, D. C. "THE PRESS AND THE FAIR", MAY 22.
  - 1962: 1st volume
    - SPEECHES
      - FLUSHING MEADOW PARK, JUNE 21, 1962 (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT BELL TELEPHONE SYSTEM GROUNDBREAKING.
      - FLUSHING MEADOW PARK, JUNE 27, 1962 (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE TRAVELERS INSURANCE COMPANIES GROUND BREAKING.
      - FLUSHING MEADOW PARK, AUGUST 14, 1962 (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT MODEL UNVEILING OF SINCLAIR DINOLAND.
      - FLUSHING MEADOW PARK, AUGUST 21, 1962 (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE EASTMAN KODAK COMPANY GROUNDBREAKING.
      - FLUSHING MEADOW PARK, SEPTEMBER 26, 1962 (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT ELECTRIC POWER & LIGHT EXHIBIT GROUNDBREAKING.
      - FLUSHING MEADOW PARK, OCTOBER 9, 1962 (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT NEW YORK STATE PAVILION GROUNDBREAKING.
      - FLUSHING MEADOW PARK, OCTOBER 16, 1962 (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT JOHNSON'S WAX GROUNDBREAKING.
      - FLUSHING MEADOW PARK, OCTOBER 31, 1962 (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT VATICAN PAVILION CEREMONIES.
      - FLUSHING MEADOW PARK, NOVEMBER 1, 1962 (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE PAVILION OF HAWAII GROUNDBREAKING.
      - FLUSHING MEADOW PARK, NOVEMBER 11, 1962 (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF B.M. AT THE PROTESTANT CENTER AT THE FAIR GROUND BREAKING.
      - FLUSHING MEADOW PARK, NOVEMBER 29, 1962 (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE REPUBLIC OF CHINA GROUNDBREAKING.
      - FLUSHING MEADOW PARK, DECEMBER 14, 1962 (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE UNITED STATES PAVILION GROUNDBREAKING.
    - REPORTS
      - FLUSHING MEADOW PARK, OCTOBER 2, 1962 (Box 4)
        THE PAVILION OF AMERICAN INTERIORS GROUNDBREAKING.
      - NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR FOLDER: INVITATION TO THE NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR 1964-1965. (Box 4)
      - NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR FOLDER: INVITATION TO THE NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR 1964-1965 (REVISED). (Box 4)
      - MARINA OF THE FUTURE--NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR 1964-1965, April 18, 1962 (Box 4)
      - NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR 1964-1965 PROGRESS REPORT #4, January 17, 1962 (Box 4)
      - NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR 1964-1965 PROGRESS REPORT #5, May 17, 1962 (Box 4)
      - NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR 1964-1965 PROGRESS REPORT #6, September 12, 1962 (Box 4)
  - 1962: 2nd volume
    - TRIBOROUGH BRIDGE AND TUNNEL AUTHORITY REPORTS:
      - DEFICIENCIES IN TRAFFIC COMMISSIONER'S PROPOSAL FOR CONSTRUCTING THE MID MANHATTAN EXPRESSWAY IN 29th STREET AND 30th STREET, MAY 1, 1962. (Box 4)
      - TRIBOROUGH BRIDGE AND TUNNEL AUTHORITY ANNUAL REPORT 1962. (Box 4)
      - ARTERIAL PROGRESS, APRIL 30, 1962. (Box 4)
      - ARTERIAL PROGRESS, OCTOBER 1, 1962. (Box 4)
    - POWER AUTHORITY OF THE STATE OF NEW YORK REPORTS:
      - POWER AUTHORITY OF THE STATE OF NEW YORK ANNUAL REPORT--1962. (Box 4)
      - NIAGARA POWER PROJECT--CONSTRUCTION PROGRESS--FIRST QUARTER 1962. (Box 4)
      - NIAGARA POWER PROJECT--CONSTRUCTION PROGRESS--SECOND QUARTER 1962. (Box 4)
      - NIAGARA POWER PROJECT--CONSTRUCTION PROGRESS--THIRD QUARTER 1962. (Box 4)
      - REPORT ON NEW YORK STATE FUTURE POWER DEVELOPMENT, DECEMBER 31, 1962. (Box 4)
      - REPORT ON FINANCING OF ST. LAWRENCE AND NIAGARA POWER PROJECTS, DECEMBER 31, 1962. (Box 4)
  - 1962: 3rd volume
    - SPEECHES AND RELEASES: 1962
      - BRUCKNER EXPRESSWAY (Box 4)
        REMARKS BY R.M. AT OPENING OF FIRST SECTION OCTOBER 18.
      - BUCKLEY, THE HON. CHAS. A. (Box 4)